Guide to the G. & C. Merriam Company Archive
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Historical File, 1804-1977; Series I; 10.8; (26 boxes)
  - DOCUMENTS AND OTHER PAPERS
    - "T" general, 1855 Jul 2 (Box 24, Folder 518)
    - Telephone, 1882-86 (Box 24, Folder 519)
    - Thomas, Joseph, 1861 May (Box 24, Folder 520)
    - Ticknor, William D., 1843 Oct 24 (Box 24, Folder 521)
    - Turner, Judson W., 1880 Feb 20 (Box 24, Folder 522)
    - "U" general, 1863, 1877 (Box 24, Folder 523)
    - United States Treasury Department, [1864] (Box 24, Folder 524)
    - "W" general, [1882] (Box 24, Folder 525)
    - Webster, Daniel, [1849] (Box 24, Folder 526)
    - Webster, Noah, 1804-54, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 527-528)
      Documents dated Oct 2 1824, Jun 1 1843, Feb 28 1852, Apr 7 1854, Apr 25 1844, Apr 12 1854, and 1856 are later typed transcripts. Documents of 26 May 1826, May 7 1833 are later autograph copies
    - Webster, William G., 1846-58, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 529)
      Memorandum of opinion, undated, is a later typed transcript
    - Webster Heirs, 1844-68, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 530-533)
      Documents dated Nov 1 1853, Feb 16 1855, May 13 1856, Sep 16 1854, and undated are later typed transcripts
    - Webster's Dictionary
      - Webster's International Dictionary, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 534)
        Documents are later typed transcripts, carbon
      - Royal Octavo Edition, 1844-67, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 535)
        Documents dated May 15 1847, Nov 20 1850, and May 13 1858 are later typed transcripts
      - Webster's Academic Dictionary, 1852-55 (Box 25, Folder 536)
      - Suggested Corrections and Additions
        - Writings, printed material, 1863-68 (Box 25, Folder 537)
        - Writings, printed material, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 538-544)
      - Covers of volumes with Suggested Corrections and Additions to Webster Dictionaries previously tipped in, 1856, n.d.
    - Wheeler, Marshall & Bruce, 1873 Jan 28 (Box 25, Folder 545)
    - Wheeler, William Adolphus, 1862-[73] (Box 25, Folder 546)
    - White, Henry, 1868 Apr 9 (Box 25, Folder 547)
    - White, Norman, 1853-56, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 548)
      Document dated Dec 24 1853, May 8 1857, Jun 2 1857 are later typed transcripts
    - White & Sheffield, [1846] (Box 25, Folder 549)
    - Wiley & Putnam, 1847 Mar, Sep (Box 25, Folder 550)
    - Willard, Carl, 1859 Jul 16 (Box 25, Folder 551)
    - Wisconsin, [1880] (Box 25, Folder 552)
    - Worcester's Dictionary, 1855-85, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 553-554)
    - Yale College, 1850 Jan 18 (Box 25, Folder 555)
    - Unidentified, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 556)
  - OTHER CORRESPONDENCE AND DOCUMENTS
    - Abstract of Contracts, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 557)
    - Merriam & Co. envelopes with notes about contents, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 558)
      Contents now interfiled in the Historical File
- Letterpress Copybooks, 1851-1905; Series II; 51.8; (65 boxes)
  Series II, Letterpress Copybooks, consists of 62 sequentially numbered letterpress copybooks, however, volumes 1 and 57-62 are lacking. These copybooks are indexed. These are followed by three unnumbered volumes dating from 1851 to 1905, with gaps.
  - Number 0: January 19, 1875 to July 8, 1877, 1875-77 (Box 27, Folder 559)
  - Number 2: February 13, 1878 to November 13, 1878 (Box 28, Folder 560)
  - Number 3: November 13, 1878 to May 21, 1879, 1878-79 (Box 29, Folder 561)
  - Number 4: May 21, 1879 to December 10, 1879 (Box 30, Folder 562)
  - Number 5: December 11, 1879 to June 1, 1880, 1879-80 (Box 31, Folder 563)
  - Number 6: June 1, 1880 to December 8, 1880 (Box 32, Folder 564)
  - Number 7: December 9, 1880 to June 6, 1881, 1880-81 (Box 33, Folder 565)
  - Number 8: June 6, 1881 to November 12, 1881 (Box 34, Folder 566)
  - Number 9: November 12, 1881 to March 18, 1882, 1881-82 (Box 35, Folder 567)
  - Number 10: March 18, 1882 to July 20, 1882 (Box 36, Folder 568)
  - Number 11: July 20, 1882 to October 25, 1882 (Box 37, Folder 569)
  - Number 12: October 25, 1882 to January 5, 1883, 1882-83 (Box 38, Folder 570)
  - Number 13: January 5, 1883 to April 18, 1883 (Box 39, Folder 571)
  - Number 14: April 19, 1883 to August 25, 1883 (Box 40, Folder 572)
  - Number 15: August 27, 1883 to November 15, 1883 (Box 41, Folder 573)
  - Number 16: November 15, 1883 to February 1, 1884, 1883-84 (Box 42, Folder 574)
  - Number 17: February 2, 1884 to May 12, 1884 (Box 43, Folder 575)
  - Number 18: May 13, 1884 to August 12, 1884 (Box 44, Folder 576)
  - Number 19: August 21, 1884 to September 17, 1884 (Box 45, Folder 577)
  - Number 20: September 18, 1884 to November 6 1884 (Box 46, Folder 578)
  - Number 21: November 7, 1884 to January 7 1885, 1884-85 (Box 47, Folder 579)
  - Number 22: January 8, 1885 to February 24, 1885 (Box 48, Folder 580)
  - Number 23: February 25, 1885 to April 24, 1885 (Box 49, Folder 581)
  - Number 24: April 25, 1885 to July 8, 1885 (Box 50, Folder 582)
  - Number 25: July 9, 1885 to September 21, 1885 (Box 51, Folder 583)
  - Number 26: September 22, 1885 to November 18, 1885 (Box 52, Folder 584)
  - Number 27: November 19, 1885 to January 6, 1886, 1885-86 (Box 53, Folder 585)
  - Number 28: January 6, 1886 to March 8, 1886 (Box 54, Folder 586)
  - Number 29: March 9, 1886 to May 17, 1886 (Box 55, Folder 587)
  - Number 30: May 18, 1886 to August 16, 1886 (Box 56, Folder 588)
  - Number 31: August 17, 1886 to October 16, 1886 (Box 57, Folder 589)
  - Number 32: October 18, 1886 to December 15, 1886 (Box 58, Folder 590)
  - Number 33: December 16, 1886 to Febuary 16, 1887, 1886-87 (Box 59, Folder 591)
  - Number 34: February 17, 1887 to April 30, 1887 (Box 60, Folder 592)
  - Number 35: May 2, 1887 to July 25, 1887 (Box 61, Folder 593)
  - Number 36: July 26, 1887 to September 29, 1887 (Box 62, Folder 594)
  - Number 37: September 30, 1887 to November 19, 1887 (Box 63, Folder 595)
  - Number 38: November 21, 1887 to January 7, 1888, 1887-88 (Box 64, Folder 596)
  - Number 39: January 9, 1888 to March 2, 1888 (Box 65, Folder 597)
  - Number 40: March 3, 1888 to May 11, 1888 (Box 66, Folder 598)
  - Number 41: May 12, 1888 to July 26, 1888 (Box 67, Folder 599)
  - Number 42: July 27, 1888 to September 28, 1888 (Box 68, Folder 600)
  - Number 43: September 29, 1888 to November 22, 1888 (Box 69, Folder 601)
  - Number 44: November 23, 1888 to January 19, 1889, 1888-89 (Box 70, Folder 602)
  - Number 45: January 21, 1889 to March 21, 1889 (Box 71, Folder 603)
  - Number 46: March 22, 1889 to June 4, 1889 (Box 72, Folder 604)
  - Number 47: June 5, 1889 to August 24, 1889 (Box 73, Folder 605)
  - Number 48: August 26, 1889 to October 24, 1889 (Box 74, Folder 606)
  - Number 49: October 25, 1889 to December 14, 1889 (Box 75, Folder 607)
  - Number 50: December 16, 1889 to February 8, 1890, 1889-90 (Box 76, Folder 608)
  - Number 51: February 10, 1890 to March 25, 1890 (Box 77, Folder 609)
  - Number 52: March 26, 1890 to May 1, 1890 (Box 78, Folder 610)
  - Number 53: May 2, 1890 to June 7, 1890 (Box 79, Folder 611)
  - Number 54: June 9, 1890 to July 11, 1890 (Box 80, Folder 612)
  - Number 55: July 12, 1890 to August 19, 1890 (Box 81, Folder 613)
  - Number 56: August 20, 1890 to September 24, 1890 (Box 82, Folder 614)
  - Number 63: March 14, 1891 to April 18, 1891 (Box 83, Folder 615)
  - Number 64: April 20, 1891 to June 3, 1891 (Box 84, Folder 616)
  - Number 65: June 4, 1891 to July 13, 1891 (Box 85, Folder 617)
  - Number 66: July 14, 1891 to September 1, 1891 (Box 86, Folder 618)
  - Number 67: September 2, 1891 to October 7, 1891 (Box 87, Folder 619)
  - Number 68: October 8, 1891 to November 4, 1891 (Box 88, Folder 620)
  - Letter copybook, 1851-55, n.d. (Box 89, Folder 621)
    Containing letters to Chauncey Goodrich; Case, Tiffany & Co.; William G. Webster on nineteen pages. At back of copybook is a list of newspapers and their circulation, undated
  - State, County, & City Superintendent's Book. Letterpress copybook: July 30, 1877 to December 12, 1878, 1877-78
    Letters to School Superintendents
  - Letterpress copybook, many letters signed O. M. Baker for G. & C. Merriam, 1880-87 (Box 89, Folder 622)
  - Letterpress copybook: July 29, 1882 to January 1905, 1882-1905
- Ledgers, 1818-1921; Series III; 1.25; (3 boxes)
  Series III, Ledgers, is organized into six subseries: Account Books, Daybooks, Merchants Books, Order Books, Inventories, and Miscellaneous Ledgers. Each subseries is arranged chronologically.
  - ACCOUNT BOOKS
    - E. Merriam & Co.; E. & G. Merriam, 1818-32
      Accompanied by separately bound index
    - E. & G. Merriam "Leger", 1824-31
    - E. Merriam & Co.; E. & G. Merriam, 1828-32
    - Ledger A. On title page: Merriam, Little & Co. August 1st, 1831. G. and C. Merriam, April 28th, 1832, 1831-36
    - Ledger B, 1836-39
    - Ledger C, 1840-44
    - Ledger D, 1843-46
    - Ledger E, 1846-49
    - Ledger, 1853-56
    - Ledger, 1856-65
    - Ledger, 1865-76
    - Ledger, 1876-77
    - Ledger, 1877-82
    - Ledger A, 1882-87
    - Ledger B April 1887-March 1889, 1887-89
    - Booksellers account book, 1843-48
      With bookseller's label of D. C. King, Law Bookseller tipped inside front cover
    - Ledger, 1845-47
    - Copyright account book, 1854-73 (Box 90, Folder 623)
    - Mutual Accounts [Accounts with George, Charles, and Homer Merriam], 1875-85 (Box 90, Folder 624)
    - Editorial accounts, 1880-90
    - Account book for orders for 1890 Webster's International Dictionary, 1891-93
  - DAYBOOKS
    - E. Merriam & Co.; E. & G. Merriam, 1828-31
    - Merriam, Little & Co.; G. &. C. Merriam. On spine: A, 1831-33
    - G & C. Merriam, 1844-45
  - MERCHANTS BOOKS
    - Merchants Accounts, No. 1, 1841-44
    - B [spine title], 1843-45
  - ORDER BOOKS
    - Merriam, Little & Co.; G. & C. Merriam, 1831-36
    - November 28, 1840 - December 31, 1842, 1840-42
    - Paper cover removed from 1840-42 order book, n.d. (Box 90, Folder 625)
    - January 2, 1842 - September 18, 1844, 1842-44
    - September 18, 1844 - December 9, 1846, 1844-46
      G. and C. Merriam advertisement pasted inside front cover
    - December 11, 1846 - January 31, 1851, 1846-51
  - INVENTORIES
    - 1858, 1860, 1863, 1864, 1866, 1869, 1873, 1858-73 (Box 90, Folder 626)
    - Invoice of property sold by G. & C. M. to H. M. January 1876 (Box 90, Folder 627)
    - Inventory, April 21, 1877. [Rough draft] (Box 90, Folder 628)
    - April 1, 1878 to April 1, 1882 inclusive. [Summary], 1878-83 (Box 90, Folder 629)
    - Inventory 1877-1878, 1877-78 (Box 90, Folder 630)
    - Inventory 1879, 1879 Apr (Box 90, Folder 631)
    - Inventory 1880, 1880 Apr (Box 90, Folder 632)
    - Inventory 1881, 1881 Apr (Box 90, Folder 633)
    - Inventory April 1882. Rough draft, 1882 Apr (Box 90, Folder 634)
    - Inventories April 1, 1882-1887, 1882-87 (Box 90, Folder 635)
    - Inventories April 1, 1888-1892, 1888-92 (Box 91, Folder 636)
    - Merriam Co. note on package containing smaller inventory booklets, 1921 (Box 91, Folder 637)
  - MISCELLANEOUS LEDGERS
    - Notes on cost of publishing Webster Dictionary, 1844-47 (Box 91, Folder 638)
      Notes on number of pages, cost of paper and printing, cost of editor
    - Between Old and New Firms -- Webster Speller Sales, 1855-68 (Box 91, Folder 639)
      Includes sales of abridgements, cost of sundries of quarto dictionary, contract with Masons, copyright account with Masons, sales of speller
    - Cost of Dictionaries and law books, 1857-1912 (Box 91, Folder 640)
      With three advertisements pasted in at back
    - Miscellaneous notes: estimates of cost, sales and profits of 1864 edition, Houghton's prices for binding, number of persons required to make 100 Webster's Dictionary per day, new words, 1864-78 (Box 91, Folder 641)
    - About new edition of the quarto: sales, 1866-1914 (Box 91, Folder 642)
      Includes sales of octavo as well. With notes on southern school systems at back, sales of Chitty, of Law
    - Sales summary, 1867-71 (Box 91, Folder 643)
    - Sales of Webster Abridgements, 1867-87 (Box 91, Folder 644)
      With Building Expenses in back, 1866
    - Office Interviews and Other Notes, From Business Books, 1879-89
      Covers period 1879 Aug 5-1889 Feb 1
    - Office interviews, 1880-1902 (Box 92, Folder 645)
      With notes on advancement of work by editors, pay rates, list of books supplied to editors. A memorandum from a letter from H.O. Houghton dated 1881 May 25 is tipped in back cover of volume
      Stored also in: Oversize, box 112, folder 728
    - Dividends and statements, 1883-92 (Box 92, Folder 646)
    - Booksellers: Rating and Terms, 1889-1901 (Box 92, Folder 647)
- Other Papers, 1797-1978; Series IV; 4.75; (9 boxes)
  Series IV, Other Papers, is organized into four subseries: Scrapbooks, Printed Ephemera, Writings, and Photographs and Postcards.
  - SCRAPBOOKS
    - Clippings and pamphlets, 1850-54
      Inside front and back covers are pasted numerous bookseller labels
    - Pages of clippings, pamphlets, circulars (disbound), [1850]-90 (Box 93, Folder 648-650)
    - Newspaper notices, "controversial" and "non-controversial", 1855-58
      "Controversial" clippings pasted in starting from the front and "non-controversial" clippings pasted in starting from the back in dos-à-dos fashion. Bookseller labels inside front cover
    - Advertisements: pamphlets and circulars, 1856-83
    - Clippings relating to Webster's Unabridged, 1864-65
    - Clippings, circulars, advertisements, pamphlets relating mainly to Webster's Unabridged, 1864-82
    - Notes on publishers, booksellers, paper companies all over the United States, 1866-70
      Notes contain personal information on owners, estimates of worth, and credit rating
    - Stationery, circulars, pamphlets, color plates, 1884-94
    - Printed advertisements and testimonials, etc., 1900-09, n.d.
    - William A. Wheeler scrapbook of clippings, pamphlets relating to Webster Dictionaries, 1860-1940
      With letter from Walter Wheeler tipped in at front, offering the Merriam Co. his father's scrapbook
    - International Dictionary, Vol. 1: Clippings, 1891-95
    - International Dictionary, Vol. 2: Clippings, 1892-1914
    - Loose material removed from International Dictionary, Vol. 2, 1897-1931 (Box 93, Folder 651)
    - International Dictionary, Vol. 3: Clippings, 1900-05
    - Loose material removed from International Dictionary, Vol. 3, 1903-05 (Box 93, Folder 652)
  - PRINTED EPHEMERA
    - Advertisements
      - "List of Books Published," circulars, 1835-90, n.d. (Box 93, Folder 653)
        List of Books Published for Mar 1846, Feb 1848, Jan 1866, Jan 1869 are photocopies
      - Clippings, [1806?]-1900, n.d. (Box 93, Folder 654-655)
        Includes full issues of "The Hampden Whig" Springfield, Mass. Vol. 4, No. 8, April 10, 1833; "The Massachusetts Teacher" Boston, May, 1859, Vol. XII, New Series, Vol. 4, No. 5 and full issue of "The Mother's Magazine" Vol. 16, No. 2, New Series Vol. II, No. 2, February 1848; "The Independent" New York, Vol. XX, No. 1029, August 20, 1868; "The Soldiers' Record" Hartford, Conn. Vol. IV, No. 5, August 12, 1871; "The Springfield Union Anniversary Issue" May 26, 1886;"No License Advocate" Springfield, Mass., December 5, 1887
        Stored also in: Oversize, box 113, folder 739 and bsd, folder 786
      - Pamphlets advertising new editions, with specimen pages, 1846-1906, n.d. (Box 93, Folder 656-659)
      - Pamphlets advertising new editions, with testimonials, 1853-55, n.d. (Box 94, Folder 660)
      - Circulars advertising new editions, 1849-96, n.d. (Box 94, Folder 661-663)
        Stored also in: Oversize, box 113, folder 740
      - Circulars and pamphlets concerning Webster vs. other dictionaries, 1855-1913, n.d. (Box 94, Folder 664)
      - The Dictionary in The School-Room, Springfield, Mass.: G. & C. Merriam, 1873 (Box 94, Folder 665)
      - The Story of A Book In Three Chapters: The Men Who Made It, How the Book is Made, a Triple Verdict, Springfield, Mass.: G. & C. Merriam Company, n.d. (Box 94, Folder 666)
    - Other Printed Ephemera
      - Clippings about Noah Webster, 1797-1958, n.d. (Box 94, Folder 667)
        Includes issue of "Merrys Museum and Parleys Magazine" Vol. XXII, No. 1, July, 1851
        Stored also in: Oversize, box 113, folder 741
      - Clippings, circulars, and pamphlets about the Merriams, 1878-1944, n.d. (Box 94, Folder 668-669)
        Includes full issue of "Scribner's Monthly" Vol. XV, No. 4, February 1878 and full issues of "The Graphic" Springfield, Mass. New Series, No. 15 & 16, July 19, 1894 and July 26, 1894 and Springfield Massachusetts, The City of Homes Compiled and Published by The New York Industrial Recorder, 1898
        Stored also in: Oversize, box 112, folders 730-731
      - Clippings: reviews of Webster dictionaries, 1845-1915, n.d. (Box 94, Folder 670-671)
        Includes bound volume containing notices of Webster dictionaries and in back of volume an incomplete draft of The Book of Talk about Common Things Designed as an introduction to the Child's Guide and to follow The Easy Primer as a reading book for children
        Includes full issues of "The Independent" New York, Vol. VII, No. 413, October 30, 1856; "The Iowa Citizen" Des Moines, Iowa Vol. III, No. 46, December 29, 1858; "Legal and Insurance Reporter" Philadelphia, Vol. II, No. 11, December 15, 1860; "Exhibitors Weekly Bulletin, News of Interest and value concerning the Exhibits at the Panama-Pacific International Exposition" Vol. VII, No. 3, October 30, 1915
        Stored also in: Oversize, box 113, 742 and bsd, folder 787
      - Circulars and clippings relating to Orthography, Etymology, and Orthoepy, 1861-69, n.d. (Box 94, Folder 672-673)
      - G. & C. Merriam Co. stationery, [187-]-1911, n.d. (Box 94, Folder 674)
      - Pamphlet, notices, rewards of merit, blank pages printed by the Merriam Co., 1836-82, n.d. (Box 95, Folder 675-676)
      - Acts and Bills relating to the purchase of Dictionaries for common schools, 1851-82, n.d. (Box 95, Folder 677)
      - Retail Price List of the American Educational Series, Ivison, Blakeman, Taylor & Co., Publishers, 1872 (Box 95, Folder 678)
      - The Story of the Merriam Family, Springfield, Mass: Clark W. Bryan & Co., Printers, 1887 (Box 95, Folder 679)
      - Webster's New International Dictionary. Galley proofs of p. 823, corrected, 1909 (Box 95, Folder 680)
      - Galley proof and page proof for an Addenda page, corrected, 1926
        Galley proof of entries from "pussyfoot" to "radio beacon." Page proof of entries from "projector" to "radio link"
      - 100th Anniversary of the Establishment of G. & C. Merriam Company, Springfield, Massachusetts, 1931 (Box 95, Folder 681)
      - Livengood, W. W. Our Heritage...An Address Delivered to the Entire Agency Force of American Book Company, 1947 (Box 95, Folder 682)
      - Dinner to Commemorate One Hundred Years of Association, H. O. Houghton and Company, G. & C. Merriam Company, 1963 (Box 95, Folder 683)
      - Forbes, E. J. The So-Called 'American Spelling.' Its Consistency Examined, n.d. (Box 95, Folder 684)
      - A leaf from Johnson's Dictionary, n.d.
      - Unidentified. Printed column from unidentified dictionary, with autograph manuscript corrections, n.d.
        Column of words "Core"-"Corn"
      - Miscellaneous printed ephemera, 1880-1937, n.d. (Box 95, Folder 685)
        Includes issue of "The Michigan Alumnus, Vol. XLIV, No. 1, October 2, 1937
        Stored also in: Oversize, box 112, folder 733
      - Engraved wood block for Royal Quarto Dictionary advertisement, n.d. (Box 95, Folder 686)
        "J. J & Co. 35 Ann St. N.Y." carved on back of block
      - Engraved wood block for Unabridged Dictionary, Illustrated advertisement, n.d. (Box 95, Folder 687)
      - Proofs of Illustrations for Dictionary
        - A-E, photoreproductions of proofs, with holograph notes, 1953-56, n.d. (Box 96, Folder 688)
        - F-P, photoreproductions of proofs, with holograph notes, 1953-56, n.d. (Box 97, Folder 689)
        - P-V, photoreproductions of proofs, with holograph notes, 1953-56, n.d. (Box 98, Folder 690)
        - V-Z, photoreproductions of proofs, with holograph notes, 1953-56, n.d. (Box 99, Folder 691)
      - Index to the Printed Material (Box 100, Folder 692)
  - WRITINGS
    - Allen, William. Word list. Holograph manuscript, 1855 (Box 101, Folder 693)
    - Goodrich, Chauncey. Preface to the Revised Edition [of 1847] by the Editor, autograph manuscript, corrected draft [incomplete], n.d. (Box 101, Folder 694)
    - Marsh, Charles Perkins. Plan of a Hand Dictionary. Holograph manuscript, signed, 1860 Apr 29 (Box 101, Folder 695)
    - Merriam, Homer. Annals of the Merriam Family. Bound holograph manuscript, 1862-1906
    - Merriam histories of Webster's Dictionaries. Bound autograph manuscript, 1883-1938
      Includes Charles Merriam's Recollections, Homer Merriam's continuation of same, copy of a letter from Noah Webster to Jonathan Barnes 1839 Dec 21, a listing of the different editions of Webster's Quarto, a copy of a letter from S. Converse to C. Merriam 1866 Jul 14, Sales of Webster's Abridgements and Webster's Unabridged
    - Loose items removed from Merriam histories volume, n.d. (Box 101, Folder 696)
    - Webster, Noah. Three leaves from the holograph draft of the 1828 edition of the Unabridged Dictionary, n.d. (Box 101, Folder 697)
      One leaf runs from "Bandit" to "Bang" and the other two run from "Brach" to "Branchy"
    - [Webster, Noah?] Holograph revisions to a printed dictionary page with tipped on pages carrying holograph additions, n.d.
      Printed dictionary pages pp. 85-86 from "Apophlegmatic" to "Apparition"
    - Webster, William G. Preface to the Academic Dictionary. Holograph manuscript, 1850 Sep (Box 101, Folder 698)
    - Unidentified. Dictionary Chart, n.d.
      Chart, dated Oct 1946, is a photocopy
    - Unidentified. A List of Noah Webster's Books. Bound autograph manuscript, 1916, n.d.
    - Loose items removed from A List of Noah Webster's Books, 1911-16, n.d. (Box 101, Folder 699)
    - Unidentified. A New Catalogue, in the Year 1858, of 1,050 words not in Webster. Autograph manuscript, 2 leaves (Box 101, Folder 700)
      From "Adaptment" to "Awardment"
    - Unidentified. New Words and Corrections Made in Plates, etc. Bound autograph manuscript, 1875-88 (Box 101, Folder 701)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS AND POSTCARDS
    - Noah Webster birthplace in West Hartford, building and furniture, [1947, 1978] (Box 101, Folder 702)
    - Noah Webster House from New Haven, Restored in Greenfield Village, Dearborn, Michigan, n.d. (Box 101, Folder 703)
    - First Printing Office of the Merriams, West Brookfield, Mass., n.d. (Box 101, Folder 704)
- Volumes, 0.8; (10 boxes)
  Volumes contains materials from Series III and IV, and is arranged in series order.
  - Editorial accounts (in Series III), 1880-90 (Box 102, Folder 705)
  - Account book for orders for 1890 Webster's International Dictionary (in Series III), 1891-93 (Box 103, Folder 706)
  - G & C. Merriam daybook (in Series III), 1844-45 (Box 104, Folder 707)
  - Order Book: November 28, 1840 - December 31, 1842 (in Series III), 1840-42 (Box 105, Folder 708)
  - Order Book: January 2, 1842 - September 18, 1844 (in Series III), 1842-44 (Box 106, Folder 709)
  - Order Book: September 18, 1844 - December 9, 1846 (in Series III), 1844-46 (Box 107, Folder 710)
  - Order Book: December 11, 1846 - January 31, 1851 (in Series III), 1846-51 (Box 108, Folder 711)
  - Office Interviews and Other Notes, From Business Books (in Series III), 1879-89 (Box 109, Folder 712)
  - Merriam histories of Webster's Dictionaries. Bound autograph manuscript (in Series IV), 1883-1938 (Box 110, Folder 713)
  - Unidentified. A List of Noah Webster's Books. Bound autograph manuscript (in Series IV), 1916, n.d. (Box 111, Folder 714)
- Oversize, 50; (40 boxes)
  Oversize contains material from series I-IV, arranged in box order.